Lorenzo Girardi

System Administrator



PERSONAL DETAILS

<u>Lorenzo Girardi</u> <u>Via cacciatori delle alpi 19</u> Castronno (Varese) italy

M: 00393402892734

E: lorenzo.girardi@gmail.com PGP

E: lorenzo@ethzero.it

E: 1@k8s.it

DOB: 16/02/1983
Driving license: YES
Nationality: Italian

AREAS OF EXPERIENCE

System administrator

Datacenter migration

Peoples coordination

Capability plans

Virtualization technology

Networking

Cloud

<u>Vpn</u>

Operating systems

HA infrastructure

HS infrastructure

Monitoring

<u>Kubernetes</u>

PCI DSS

PERSONAL SUMMARY

A highly competent and organized system administrator with experience both in high scalability environment and in high availability.

Autonomous management of large projects and implementation with the latest smart tools.

Extensive knowledge of monitoring and controlling of applications behavior and data security within guidelines to ensure compliance and report on possible improvements.

Able in team working in order to reach the business goal.

Interested in a new challenges, in my experience i've joined in a several data center migration from 20+ to 400+ servers.

Continuously improving my knowledge on new technologies.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SRE Team Leader - BravoNEXT sa

mid 2016 - present

System administrator - BravoNEXT sa

january 2012 - mid 2016

Acting as technical lead to identify and implement new projects in a large environment 1500+ servers 90% linux 10% windows.

Duties:

- maintenance existing environment
- improve high <u>disponibility</u> of applications through open source software solutions and physical appliance
- monitoring server and applications java / .net in order to evaluate capability plans and virtual machines requirements
- network structure in way to have less complexity keeping PCI rules
- planning new projects from scratch, choosing best environment available
- puppet modules configurations
- tomcat/springboot configurations
- active directory, openIdap, ms dns, bind
- linux machines configurations, sssd ,disk acl,lvm,init
- windows machines iis /sql
- vm infrastructure management 800+ linux server centos 6 and 7
- kubernetes infrastructure management 70+ nodes 1400+ pods

PERSONAL SKILLS

Technically minded

Pro-active

Analitycal

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

<u>java – tomcat – jboss –springboot</u> – docker – javamelody – jmx

.net - iis - sql server - cluster WSFC - alwaysON - iis ARR cluster NLB

<u>apache - mod balancer - mod</u> <u>proxy balancer - mod jk - mod</u> <u>cluster</u>

nginx - vts module - ingress - traefik

vmware esxi - veeam backup / replication

rhev - ovirt

AWS - s3 - vpc - peering loadbalancer - cloudformation opsworks

<u>Azure - powershell cli - database</u> <u>as service</u>

<u>puppet - jenkins - pipeline - rundeck - spacewalk</u>

Monitoring - nagios handlers - cacti - grafana - collectd - influxdb - carbon

<u>Idap - active directory - bind -</u> <u>domain trust - domain hierarchy</u>

openswan - site to site - road warriors

<u>k8s – kubernetes – docker –</u> flanneld – etcd

google cloud platform

- cluster management RHEV, vmware esxi
- infrastructure management 100+ windows servers 2008-2012
- solution architect MS sql environment in HA and LB for IIS applications
- solution architect AWS environment s3 vpc peering
- solution architect Azure environment
- network management ipsec open source strongswan , openswan and cisco and fortinet
- develop and maintaining kubernetes cluster
- coordinate people in projects ,following all technical details and implementations
- PCI DSS management and infrastructure design

System administrator - Luxury Goods International LGI sa

contractor Temera sa 2011-2012 contractor IT Time sa 2010-2011

managing and responsible of end users tools, vpn cisco, active directory structure, lotus domino server and a first levelcontact for as400

Duties:

- Managing Mail Server Domino
- Management of mobile service on Blackberry
- Configuration and management VPN Cisco
- Active Directory management GPO
- AS400 jda , jd Edwards

System administrator - Eprice srl

2008-2010

System administrator CED Gallarate and business farm Milano

Duties:

- Management remote data center on Colt (Milano) iNET (Settimo Milanese)
- Configuration windows and linux server based on vmware esx4 and esxi 4.1
- Deploy and configuration windows server 2000, 2003, 2008 standard enterprise for business solution
- Deploy and configuration linux server for advanced internal

- solution (samba server, hw monitoring, performance monitoring, web employee portal , vpn server)
- Iscsi and fiber storage configuration and management
- Configuration and management of workstations working on Windows Xp e Windows 7.
- Server backup management tape DELL
- Network develop for company and other 30+ corner site

OTHER LANGUAGES

	Understanding		Speaking		Writing
	Listening	Reading	interaction	production	
English	B2	B2	B2	B2	B2
French	A2	A2	A2	A2	A2

EDUCATION

- 2003-2008
 Università degli studi dell'Insubria facoltà di informatica Information technology
- 1997- 2002 Pier Luigi Nervi I.T.Geometri